<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Notebook Research (HRIA project) on R. Álvarez Ugarte - sitio personal</title>
    <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Notebook Research (HRIA project) on R. Álvarez Ugarte - sitio personal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es</language>
    <copyright>R. Álvarez Ugarte</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arevalo 2013</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/arevalo2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/arevalo2013/</guid>
      <description>Is an International Corporate Human Rights liability framework needed? An Economic Power, Business and Human Rights, and American Extraterritorial Jurisdiction analysis, by Carlos Arevalo (2013)
Arevalo presents argument for a need for a liability structure that reflects an inability of states (or unwillingness) to hold corporate actors accountable and the reality that most big corporations are more powerful than States.
His perspective makes BSR FB Myanmar report’s efforts to disclaim the potential to have meaningful impact on the human rights situation in the country questionable and not reflective of real power that a corporation, especially one that has power over information its users see about all aspects of life, have contemporarily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Myanmar HRIA</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/fb_myanmar_hria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/fb_myanmar_hria/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Myanmar HRIA
High Level Takeaways
  Lack of cohesion or kind of connection of dots that would be necessary to make the report informative or actionable
 Despite the amount of report space that is devoted to contextualizing the current human rights environment in Myanmar, there is a lack of detail to its assessment and the abstract, broad approach taken fail to provide the reader with an accurate sense of who the rightsholders are and what is really at stake in terms of human rights in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esteves, 2012</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/esteves2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/esteves2012/</guid>
      <description>  @esteves2012 ON SIA
 http://iaia.org/ &amp;ldquo;SIA is widely practised internationally as a predictive study that is part of the regulatory approval process for infrastructure and resource extraction project&amp;rdquo; 35 HRIA is different    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harrison 2011</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/harrison2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/harrison2011/</guid>
      <description>@harrison2011 &amp;mdash; se concentra en HR due dilligence y dice que Ruggie2008 y Ruggie2011 sólo pueden ser efectivos si hay (a) transparencia; (b) verificaicón y particiación externa y (c) independent review.
 &amp;ldquo;Therefore, for the HRDD principle to be deemed effective and valuable, it must lead to widespread adoption of robust and meaningful HRDD processes by corporations globally, which, as a result, lead to improved human rights performance on the ground (Melish &amp;amp; Meidinger 2012).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jochnick, 1999</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/jochnick1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/jochnick1999/</guid>
      <description>Jochnick 1999 &amp;mdash; Single focus on State action endures, neds to be revisited. Foco en Ecuador (key). Hay una dimensión problemática en el ejercicio comparativo: empresas como Texaco operan en zonas de frontera y actúan como &amp;ldquo;un estado en sí mismo&amp;rdquo;; difícil la analogía con las ICT. Mucha defensa del &amp;ldquo;rights rethoric&amp;rdquo; + cambios en los 1990 que llevan a una creciente &amp;ldquo;juridización&amp;rdquo; de las actividades privadas (key, p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kemp, 2013</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/kemp2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/kemp2013/</guid>
      <description>@kemp2013 [Seguir por acá]
  &amp;ldquo;heavy foot-print industries&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; ITC es así?
  Due diligence, revolucionario &amp;mdash; emerge circa 2010, ver [@ruggie2010] &amp;mdash; Necesidad de interpelar al business para que icnorporen el lenguaje de DDHH, pero note risk
  Ruggie was not specific on the form that impact assessment should take. Nonetheless, there are several companies that now undertake or require a dedicated HRIA as a part of doing business (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paust, 2001</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/paust2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/paust2001/</guid>
      <description> Paust 2001 &amp;mdash; Tiene una ineresante revisión de los casos en EEUU que derivaron en responsabilidad de empresas por violaciones de DDHH + cómo los &amp;ldquo;instrumentos internacionales&amp;rdquo; suelen alcanzar a los &amp;ldquo;private perpatrators&amp;rdquo;.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ratner, 2001</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/ratner2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/ratner2001/</guid>
      <description>Ratner 2001 &amp;mdash; Nice theoretical / historical framework: the &amp;ldquo;swinging pendulum&amp;rdquo;. His theory: &amp;ldquo;deriving such duties based on four factors: the corporation&amp;rsquo;s ties with the government, its nexus to affected populations, the particular human right at issue, and the structure of the corporate entity.&amp;rdquo;
  The historical perspective sheds light on the role of transnational corporations in investment and human rights violations (some activitiy in the 1980s / 1990s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelne</title>
      <link>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ramiroau.github.io/onr/timeline/</guid>
      <description>1969 - NEPA EEUU (EIA) - SIA 1970 - Rico ACT (EEUU) 1970s - Soft Law [@kinley2004, 949-951] 1976 - The OECD&amp;rsquo;s 1976 Guidelines for Multinational Enterprises 1977 - The ILO&amp;rsquo;s 1977 Tripartite Declaration of Principles Concerning Multinational Enterprises and Social Policy 1977 - The Sullivan Principles (for working in South Africa) https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sullivan_principles 1980s - The MacBride principles https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacBride_Principles 1980 - ATCA (EEUU) (se empieza a usar, era parte del Judiciary Act 1789) 1990 - Shell en Nigeria [@kemp2013, 87] 1991 - Convention on Environmental Impact Assessment in a Transboundary Context (EIA) TVPA Act (EEUU) ?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>